So for those who don't know, I went to Cuba for the last week with the organization IFCO, Pastors for Peace.
I think for some people, they think solidarity is simply just like, you know, giving stuff to people who need it.
That is charity.
Solidarity is showing support beyond material goods, but also in values in order to protect the efforts that are being laid out on the ground and that have caused the need for the support.
So when we look at Cuba and we understand that Cuba has suffered greatly for standing against imperialism, we remember that many of us are benefiting from imperialism in many a way.
And so the solidarity is shown because it is also us knowing that it is our responsibility as people who are benefiting, even if we are not the ones enacting it, to do the counter work that our government is doing.
We should be acting against the way that our government is committing harm.
If we want to say that we are not our government, it is just the United States.
If we want to be on that wave, then we have to actually do that in action.
We have to do that, not just with our voice.
We have to do that with our funds.
We have to do that with our time.
We have to do that with our bodies, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Because I know for me, there's been a human to human concept around it.
But I had kind of missed the necessity to show up in solidarity because this nation has carried out a revolution that demonstrated for us that which we have yet to be seen in our own country, but that we should see in our own country.
Free health care, access to schooling, et cetera.
We've got to be a better way.